=-SF字幕同好会-=
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
翻译&校对：gcthor@HDC,转载请保留信息
片名：三星大厨
THE CHEF
奶油香煎比目鱼，2号桌！
Sole meunière, table 2!
11号桌的炖小牛肉
Blanquette for 11.
鞑靼牛排
Steak tartare.
法式牛排，夏多布里昂牛排和薯条
Entrecôte, château Briand,
and fries.
别管装饰了，那家伙只有20分钟时间吃饭
Forget the decorations.
The guy has 20 minutes to eat.
- 还没好
- 8号桌的勒庞尚干红
- That's not enough.
- Faugères for table 8.
- 他们是不是吃的小牛肉？
- 对
- Aren't they having veal?
- Yes.
- 你们点了勒庞尚干红？
- 对
You ordered Faugères?
- Yes.
- 我可以问下为什么吗？
- 服务生推荐的
- Can I ask why?
- The waiter suggested it.
糟糕的建议
Damned boozehound.
吃炖小牛肉的话，试试用干白配餐
With a veal blanquette,
try a dry white.
- 比如2003年的麝香干白葡萄酒
- 我们比较喜欢红酒
- For example, a 2003 Muscadet.
- We prefer red.
你们喜欢红酒？没问题
You prefer red?
No problem.
那样子的话，牛排和薯条更适合
In that case, steak and
fries would be a safer bet.
我的炖牛肉！
My blanquette!
不能再给我次机会吗？
Can't I have one more chance?
- 才一周啊
- 不行
Just a week.
- No.
你没意识到吗？你搅了6个人的餐点！
Don't you realize? You
attacked 6 people over meat!
- 他们要7分熟的羊肉！
- 那有怎么样？
- They wanted their lamb medium!
- So what?
你差点就打了那个在比目鱼上加芥末的家伙
You almost hit a guy
who put mustard on his sole.
博古斯说了什么？
What does Bocuse say?
别再提博古斯的那些废话了
Bocuse can blow it
out his ass.
我们不是正式餐厅
We don't do fine dining.
4岁第一次做了巴斯克鸡片，5岁第一次做了舒芙蕾
First Basque chiken at 4,
first soufflé at 5.
他们说我是那个区域的莫扎特
They say I'm
the Mozart of the range.
哪里的莫扎特？
Mozart of the what?
厨房里的…
The kitchen range...
我知道所有大厨的食谱
I know all the big
chefs' recipes.
我是个烹饪能手
I'm a culinary whiz.
先生们，大家好
Hello, gentlemen.
- 你是新来的
- 是的
- You're new here.
- Yes.
- 牛排和薯条
- 炖肉和薯条
- Steak and fries.
- Meat stew and fries.
我要鲱鱼和薯条
I'll have the herring
and some fries.
严肃点，先生们
Let's get serious. Men, please.
今天我推荐给大家的是白核桃慕斯
Today I suggest
a butternut squash mousse
和栗子骨牌以及配在栎叶生菜上的番茄意大利水饺
with chestnut dominoes and
tomato ravioli on oak leaf lettuce.
配薯条吗？
Come with fries?
配撒有辣椒粉的甜菜根
It comes with beets
à la paprika,
加胡萝卜沫的西洋菜汤
watercress soup
with carrot foam
以及少量阿金库尔醋
and a dash of
Azincourt vinegar.
这白痴是谁？
Who's this faggot?
带着你那些辣椒废话滚开！
Beat it, you and
your paprika crap!
杰克，终于要买你的大厨装了？
So Jacky?
Finally buying your chef's outfit?
很快，很快，你会见到的
Soon.
Soon, you'll see.
在牛肉上撒些面包屑
Sprinkle the beef
with breadcrumbs
和融化的黄油
and melted butter.
丁香，碎橙皮
Cloves.
Orange rinds.
工作做的如何了？
How did work go?
不是吧，杰克！一个月里被炒了4次？
No, Jacky!
Fired 4 times in 4 weeks!
很快我们就是三个人了！
Soon there will be
three of us!
他们根本不理解我
They don't understand me, at all.
- 看到我们的透支额没？
- 是的，我知道
- See our overdraft?
- Yeah, I know.
- 怎么了？
- 没事…
- What is it?
- I'm fine...
你还好吗，亲爱的？
You okay, baby?
你确定？
Are you sure?
你应该要休产假了
You have to stop working.
我会想办法找个工作的
And I'll find a way
to get a job.
- 任何工作，这样你就可以休息了
- 任何工作？
- Any job. So you can relax.
- Any job?
我找到的第一个
First one I find.
而且保证不被炒
And I won't get fired.
主厨好…
Hello, chef...
很高兴能见到大家
It's nice to leave
the ovens.
- 东西还好吗？
- 非常美味
- Is all well?
- Delicious.
- 这比目鱼如何？
- 完美
- How was the sole?
- Perfect.
喜欢我的洋葱鸭腿吗？
Do you like my
onions confit?
- 相当好吃
- 让我来
- Fit to be devoured.
- Allow me.
尝尝这一口
The perfect mouthful.
我会记住这个味道的
I'll remember that.
我该怎么支持？
How do I eat?
用餐叉叉着吃…
You stab it with a fork...
主厨！
Chef!
- 不好意思
- 没事
- Excuse me.
- Of course.
你有义务给马特先生看菜单
You're legally bound
to show Mr. Matter the menu.
我现在没时间
I have no time.
他也会解释其他的餐厅
He'll explain
about the other restaurants.
晚点再说，马丽恩
Later, Marion.
这样不行
It's no good.
我吃不出情感
I feel no emotion.
- 给我香草
- 给
- Give me the vanilla.
- Yes, chef.
尝尝
Taste it.
非常好，主厨
Very good, chef.
- 棒极了，主厨
- 没道理
- Fantastic, chef.
- Nonsense.
不能做为春季菜单
Not for the Spring menu.
我已经想尽一切了
I'm getting nowhere.
马特先生送来了一份菜单
Mr. Matter sent over a menu.
他想让你用这份
He wants you to use it.
他快要惹恼我了，跟我来
He's starting to piss me off.
Follow me.
- 别一脸忧郁了
- 我没有
- Stop moping.
- I'm not.
你说过你会做任何事
You said you'd do anything.
我是说过，而且我正在做
I said it and I'm doing it.
- 不就6个月嘛
- 一下子就过去了
- It's just for 6 months.
- It'll whiz by.
祝一天愉快
Have a good day.
- 我想我会喜欢上这的
- 加油
- I think I'll like it here.
- Go on.
所有的窗都需要重刷
All the windows need
to be repainted.
总共524扇
524 all together.
然后…
Next...
188扇门…
the doors... 188.
很好
Great.
- 他们在吃什么？
- 不知道，管他呢
- What are they eating?
- No idea. Who cares?
你的工作服
Your overalls.
- 你的工具…又好又快
- 好的，谢谢
- Your equipment... Nice and fast.
- Ok, thanks.
你好，夫人
Hello, ma'am.
洋姜
Jerusalem artichokes.
清炖肉汤
Consommé.
南瓜西班牙凉菜汤
Squash gazpacho.
这都是上世纪的菜单了 ，亚历山大
This is a menu
from the last century, Alexandre.
我们需要一些原材料来降低价格
We need ingredients
to lower the prices
比如冷冻食物和微波炉食物
of our frozen food
and microwave meals.
这和我有什么关系？
How am I concerned?
你可以帮我们获得政府许可
You can help us
get government approval.
如果卡古·拉加德使用了这些食材
If Cargo Lagarde uses
these ingredients,
我们就能得到
we'll get it.
我要为了你的股东而在我的食物中加这些垃圾？
I am to put that crap in my food
for your stockholders?
我的化学家说这毫无风险
My chemists say it's risk-free.
很多大厨与工业合作
Many big chefs work
with the industry.
- 再考虑一下
- 我已经考虑过了
- Think it over.
- I already have.
你看，你已经不适合待在这里了
You see?
You're out of place here.
这是西里尔
This is Cyril.
伦敦和巴黎的两星大厨
Two stars in London and Paris.
到我的餐馆来尝尝
Come eat at my restaurant.
磷光萝卜慕斯，沸腾牛里脊肉
Phosphorescent radish mousse,
effervescent sirloin,
还有用自由放养的鸡肉做成的冰块
and free-range
chicken ice-cubes.
令人吃惊！
Amazing!
我将要把卡古·拉加德给西里尔
I'm giving Cargo Lagarde to Cyril.
你会得到奥尔良的含羞草农舍
You'll take the Mimosa Farmhouse,
in Orléans.
看，那里多漂亮
Look how pretty it is.
对于你的传统菜肴来说是个绝佳的场所
A perfect setting
for your hearty traditional cuisine.
卡古·拉加德里有我的名字
Cargo Lagarde bears my name.
你的名字也是我们的，我们已经买下了
Your name is ours. We bought it.
你太贵了，不适合赚钱
You cost too much.
You're not profitable.
我是不能被解雇的，斯坦尼斯拉斯，重新看下我的合同吧
I can't be fired, Stanislas.
Reread my contract.
这次会面结束了
This meeting is over.
什么？
What?
这就是现实，是这样的时代，没有其他的选择
It's how it is. It's the times.
No choice.
有人在敲窗
Someone knocked.
你是怎么做鳕鱼的？
How are you doing the cod?
- 他想要干嘛？
- 鳕鱼！
- What does he want?
- The cod!
- 你是怎么做的？
- 我们听不到！
- How are you doing it?
- We can't hear! What?
你们在煮鳕鱼
You're boiling it.
用一个双层锅，最多10分钟
Use a double-boiler instead,
10 minutes tops.
不然味道会走掉的
It loses its flavor otherwise.
会变成…
It becomes...
开窗
Open the window.
- 你是怎么做这个的？
- 在盐水里烫一下
- How are you cooking it?
- Boiled in salted water.
不行！会变的没有味道的！
Don't! It will be bland!
- 你在干什么？
- 拿好
- What are you doing?
- Hold this.
我们能做的更好的
We can do better.
那么…
So...
我想做一份鲍鱼酱
I'm thinking,
a concassé of sea prince...
配柠檬慕斯
with lemon mousse.
他们不喜欢改变，他们会生气的
They hate change here.
They get nasty.
他们甚至不知道他们吃的什么
They don't even know
what they eat.
昨天他们把鱼当成了鸡肉
Yesterday
they mistook fish for chicken.
如果你们听我的话
If you listen to me,
我们会达到烹饪的顶峰
we'll reach the peak
of culinary creation.
这又不是我们所追求的
That's not what we're after.
你给我们做了什么？
What did you put in our plates?
装在芦笋筏上的鲍鱼酱柠檬慕斯
Concassé of sea prince
with a lemon mousse
配以彩虹色酱料做点缀
on an asparagus raft
with rainbow polka-dot sauce.
我不喜欢鳕鱼
I don't like codfish.
- 先尝一下
- 我不喜欢！
- Taste it first.
- But I don't like it!
我们这个年纪的人知道自己喜欢什么！
At our age we know if we
like something or not!
- 我只要土豆泥！
- 我不喜欢黄色的东西
- Only mashed potatoes!
- No yellow stuff for me.
这咖啡从来都不热！
The coffee is never hot enough!
滚开！
Get lost!
别伤心，油漆工，这很正常
Don't worry, Paint Boy.
It's normal.
有次我被打就因为在煎蛋卷里放了奶酪
I once put cheese in an omelet
and I got bit!
是我的错，我太自大了
It's my fault. I see too big.
人们从不关心质量
People don't care about quality.
对不起，伙计们
Sorry, guys.
对了
You know what?
下次
Next time,
给他们上捣碎的阿司匹林配安定果汁
give them mashed aspirin
with Valium juice.
他们会喜欢的
They'll love it.
我要这个鼠尾草
I'll take the sage.
5分钟后直播，只有一根葱
Live in 5 minutes.
Just one leek.
我妈妈很崇拜你，可以签个名吗？
My mother adores you.
Can I have an autograph?
2分钟后直播
Live in 2 minutes.
我想告诉你…我要离开卡古·拉加德了
I meant to say...
I'm leaving Cargo Lagarde.
什么？
What?
去掌管纽约的巴黎镜餐馆
To run Miroir de Paris
in New York.
我还没决定了
I haven't decided yet.
斯坦尼斯拉斯已经和我签了合同
Stanislas Matter
already signed me on.
- 我希望你能原谅我
- 你不能这样做！
- I hope you'll forgive me.
- You can't do this!
我教了你这么多东西！
I taught you what
a paupiette was!
1分钟后直播
Live in 1 minute.
我无法拒绝巴黎镜
I couldn't refuse
Miroir de Paris.
但不是现在！
But not now!
所有人都在等着我那该死的春季菜单
Everyone is lying in wait
for my fucking Spring menu.
你永远在我心中
You remain in my
heart and head.
去你的！
Screw your heart
and your head!
听到了吗？
Hear me?
对不起，但是…我也要离开了
Sorry but... I'm leaving too.
10秒
Ten seconds.
他要送我去迪拜的法国雄鸡餐馆
He named me to Coq de France
in Dubai.
- 对不起
- 你们是联合起来对付我吗？
- I'm sorry.
- Are you all in on this?
欢迎观看我的节目
Welcome to my show,
“亚历山大市场”
"Alexandre's Market".
今天仍旧是由我，以及…
Here I am, along with...
我的助手，塞尔吉奥
my faithful assistants, Sergio
和明夫来主持
and Akio.
- 开始了吗？
- 刚开始
- Did it start?
- Just now.
今天
Today,
我会教大家我最喜欢的开胃菜
I'll teach you
one of my favorite starters.
在寒冷的冬天，当你回到家…
In the cold of winter,
when you're home...
这个节目我简直喜欢的发狂
Crazy how I'm hooked
to this show.
我也一样
Same here.
想要暖一暖身体，我建议
To warm your heart, I suggest
法式忌廉汤
a leek soup
配洋槐蜂蜜
with acacia honey.
- 葱和蜂蜜能放一起？
- 当然！
- You can cook leeks with honey?
- Sure!
- 你知道？
- 会有人不知道？
- You knew?
- Who doesn't?
安静！
Quiet!
把葱切成块
Cut the leek into cubes.
只要葱白
Just the white part.
是的，明夫，就像我这么多年里教给你的一样
Yes, Akio. Like I taught you
all these years by my side.
他表现的很古怪
He's acting weird.
在洋葱变黄前，加入葱块
Before the onions brown,
add the leeks.
他从不用洋葱
He never used onions.
这意味着…
It means...
他在担心什么
he has worries.
工作或者女人
Something with work
or a woman.
- 你认识他？
- 心里
- Know him?
- By heart.
我常常学他的菜谱
I used to steal his books
and offer them to myself.
好玩吗？一扇窗要用多久？
Having fun?
How long can one window take?
- 我忘记我的刷子了
- 那里还有一边
- I forgot my brush.
- There's another wing.
好的，我尽快
Okay. I'll just be a sec.
- 再见
- See you later.
- See you.
我刚只是在…润色
I was just... touching up.
你能不能来帮两个星期的忙？
You can't get away
for two weeks?
我需要一个副手
I need a second-in-command.
爸爸，我论文答辩的日子定下来了
Dad, I got the date
for my thesis!
你认识谁有空的吗？
You know anyone
who may be available?
我试过了
I already tried him.
那么就是没有了…
So no one...
宝贝，你回来了！
Honey, you're home!
我刚在里面和你说过话了
I just spoke to
you in there.
我知道你刚和我说过话
I know you spoke
to me in there!
那我说了什么？
What did I say?
是关于…
It was about something...
- 你会来吗？
- 当然…去哪？
- Are you coming?
- Of course I am... Where?
我的论文答辩
My thesis defense.
是关于什么的？
What's it about?
俄罗斯奇幻文学以及19世纪的小说
Russian fantastic literature
and the 19th century novel.
我的餐馆里俄罗斯人也越来越多了
We have more and more Russians
at the restaurant.
很好
Great.
你会来吗？
You going?
我要工作，我没有做这个安排，你生气了？
I'm working. It wasn't planned.
Are you upset?
我了解了，去不去是你的事，没什么大不了的
I figured. Canceling is your thing.
No big deal.
别这样，别再吃汉堡了
Come on,
not another hamburger.
我是拉加德小姐
It's Miss Lagarde.
我想要双份奶酪和一杯可乐
I'd like a double
cheese and a Coke.
谢谢，再见
Thanks. Goodbye.
祝晚上愉快，爸爸！
Have a good night, Dad!
杰克，我们要好吃的！
Jacky, we want food!
我们要昨天一样的东西！
We want the same
thing as yesterday!
我们要杰克做的东西！
We want Jacky's food!
- 我和你儿子之间出了点问题
- 怎么了？
- I have trouble with your son.
- How so?
他想让我用胶凝剂，该死的化学物
He wants me to use gelling agents,
chemical shit.
我明白了,尝尝这个
I see.
Taste this.
我麻烦大了,保罗
I'm in deep shit, Paul.
我找不到灵感
I have no inspiration.
你每年都怕失去一颗星
Same thing every year.
You think you'll lose a star.
来尝一下
Just taste.
这是什么？
What is it?
不可思议
Incredible.
就是这反应
That's the word.
我1996年的红鲣和南瓜食谱
My red mullet and pumpkin recipe
from 1996!
正是
Exactly.
不可思议，简直一模一样
It's wild. It's all there.
蔬菜的平衡
The balance of vegetables,
香料的协调，一切！
the harmony of spices.
Everything!
这是谁做的？
Who made this?
看到那个油漆工了吗？
See that painter there?
那个油漆工？
The painter?
打扰一下，可以聊一下吗？
Excuse me,
can we talk a bit?
这个96年的红鲣和南瓜和是你做的吗？
Is it you who made my recipe
for mullet and pumpkin from '96?
不，是97年的
No, '97.
96年是圣皮尔土豆泥
In '96 it was St.Pierre
and potato mousseline.
- 你确定？
- 绝对
- Are you sure?
- You bet!
对我来说，那食谱就像大卫之于米开朗基罗
For me, that recipe
was like Michelangelo's David.
有趣的比喻
Interesting analogy.
我需要一个副手
I need a second-in-command.
你愿意到卡古·拉加德来实习吗？
Would you work on a trial basis
at Cargo Lagarde?
我能拿到合同吗？
But I'll get a contract?
- 先试用，然后再决定
- 多久？
- A trial. Then we'll see.
- How long?
法律所规定的，一个月，两个…
Whatever the law says.
One month, two...
对不起，我不去
I'm sorry. I can't.
我在这有份6个月的合同，我妻子已经怀孕了
I have a 6-month contract here.
My wife is pregnant.
- 她会理解的
- 她不会的
- She'll understand.
- No, she won't.
你不能拒绝卡古·拉加德！
You can't say no
to Cargo Lagarde!
你是个白痴吗？
Are you a total idiot?
对不起，先生，我爱我妻子，仅此而已
No, sir. I love my wife.
That's all.
你们一个个的快要惹恼我了！
You're all starting to
piss me off. Big time!
拉加德先生，等等！
Mr. Lagarde, wait!
我接受你的提议
I accept your offer.
好吧…明早8点卡古见
Fine... Tomorrow at
8 at the Cargo.
你是对的，我会告诉我妻子真相的
You're right.
I'll tell my wife the truth.
当然…
Of course...
她会理解我的，为了一份免费的实习工作
she'll understand
that I left...
而放弃一份工作合约
a paid job for an
unpaid internship.
- 这是什么？
- 美丽的鲜花
- What's that?
- They're flowers.
- 你在这干嘛？
- 接你
- Why are you here?
- To pick you up.
我想让你知道你现在可以依靠我了
I like knowing
you can count on me now.
- 你被炒了？
- 没有的事
- You got fired?
- Not at all.
那是怎么回事
Something serious.
你到底要不要？
Do you want them or not?
当然，你抱着吧，我可是怀孕了
Of course I do. You carry them.
I'm a little pregnant.
猜猜发生了什么
Guess what happened.
我就知道发生了什么事情
I knew there was something.
是的，是发生了一些事情
Yeah, there was something.
猜猜谁夸奖了我
Guess who congratulated me.
谁？
Who?
亚历山大…
Alexandre...
养老院的经理
The manager of the
old-age facility.
他说我刷的很快，他想让我刷掉整个养老院
He says I paint fast.
He wants me to do the whole place.
对准了厨房？
Zeroing in on the kitchen?
没有，厨房远的很呢
You're crazy. The kitchen
is miles away!
别这样！
Stop it!
亚历山大！住手！
Alexandre! Stop this!
马特先生让我们来的！
Mr. Matter sent us!
下次我会把你们扔进冷藏室！
Next time I'll throw
you in the meat locker!
- 早，主厨
- 你迟到了
- Morning, chef.
- You're late.
- 才8：02
- 这就是我想说的，你迟到了
- It's 8:02.
- That's what I said. You're late!
珍妮！
Janine!
帮他的制服上绣上名字
Embroider his initials.
- 好的
- 我叫杰克·波诺
- Of course.
- It's Jacky Bonnot.
等下
Hold on.
只是想表达下谢意
Only normal.
"我想说的是，主厨
"I wanted to say, chef,
很感谢你给我的这个机会"
I am aware of the chance
you're giving me."
“实际上，当我还是个不懂事的孩子时
"Indeed, as a mere child,
您的菜谱对我来说就已经像项链上的珠子…”
your recipes were like
beads in a necklace..."
厨房见
See you in the kitchen.
好吧，我马上来
Okay.
I'll be right there.
那是马塞尔·布夏尔…
That's Marcel Bouchard...
- 给
- 谢谢
- Here.
- Thanks.
这个围裙要陪伴我很久了
This apron and I have
a long life ahead.
那就先从今天不被炒掉开始吧
Start by not getting
fired today.
注意了，所有人
Everyone,
your attention please.
尝下这个然后告诉我里面有什么
Taste this and tell
me what's in it.
- 要蒙住眼睛吗？
- 这里不是音乐厅
- Blindfolded?
- This isn't a music hall.
那么…
So...
烤大比目鱼
Roasted turbot.
配上菠菜酱
With a spinach coulis.
这个酱汁是…番茄和橄榄
The sauce is...
tomato and olive.
萝卜，盐黄油
Daikon radish,
salted butter.
我想应该再多加一点点盐
I'd have added a
pinch more salt.
很好
Very good.
这个闻起来像什么？
What does that smell like?
细嫩可口的烤牛肉
Confit of grilled beef.
精选的牛肉，完美的选择
Vintage Select Beef,
excellent choice.
西葫芦和土豆…
Zucchini and potatoes...
质地上乘
Lady Christels,
excellent texture.
他们在沸水里很稳定
They stay firm
in boiling water.
一点烤茄子…
A little grilled eggplant...
烤过头了
Over-grilled.
烤的太过了，如果要我说的话
Way over-grilled, if I may.
他是对的，这个茄子烤过头了
He's right.
This eggplant is over-grilled.
这是谁做的？
Who made this?
我
I did.
我告诉过你，茄子是很柔弱的
I've told you.
Eggplants are touchy.
别伤害它们，要紧盯着它们
Don't hurt them.
Look them straight in the eye.
我一直看着！
I looked it in the eye!
- 倒掉它
- 好的，主厨
- Toss it.
- Yes, chef.
显然你是不会犯这种错误的
Obviously,
you'd never have done that.
当然不会，我就好像听到那个茄子在尖叫一样
No, chef.
I'd have heard the eggplant scream.
杰克是一个蔬菜语者
Jacky is the vegetable
whisperer.
以及听众，这很重要
And listener.
That's important.
这个胡萝卜在说什么？
What's this carrot saying?
磨我
Grate me.
它想被磨碎
It wants to be grated.
- 磨掉它
- 是，主厨
- Grate it.
- Yes, chef.
做圣皮尔用
For the St. Pierre.
杰克今天会看你们工作，明天他会开始做事
Jacky will watch you work today.
Tomorrow, he'll run both services.
- 回去工作
- 是，主厨！
- Get to work.
- Yes, chef!
我被录用了，主厨？
So I'm hired, chef?
等到了忙时再说吧，很多人做不好
Wait until rush hour.
Many a man returns his apron.
- 不会是杰克·波诺
- 到时候就知道了
- Not Jacky Bonnot.
- We'll see.
这是什么？
What's this?
牛羊砸碎，扇贝，香草…
Sweetbread, scallops, vanilla...
忘了那些吧，制作菜谱是我的事情
Forget that.
I do the creating.
我是在想…
I was thinking...
了解
Got it.
我感觉非常好
I feel so good.
摸摸看…我们的孩子也在休息呢
Touch... Our baby is relaxed too.
这都要感谢全新的杰克
It's thanks to the new Jacky.
全新的杰克…
New Jacky....
别过火了
Don't go overboard.
我想告诉你…我辞职了
I meant to tell you...
I quit my job.
我已经和亚历山大·拉加德在一起3天了
I've been with Alexandre Lagarde
for 3 days.
这是一份实习，所以目前没有工资
It's an internship,
so unpaid for the moment.
对不起，我都快睡着了
Sorry, I'm half asleep.
你刚刚说了什么？
What did you say?
晚安，我全新的杰克…
Goodnight, my new Jacky...
- 怎样？
- 满座了，主厨
- How is it?
- Full, chef.
- 海蜇虾在哪？
- 来了！
- Where are the langoustines?
- Coming, chef!
鸡肉应该是要做好了！
The chicken should
be ready by now!
我的嫩煎小牛肉片还没好！
I still need my piccatas!
我知道了
I'll get them.
- 对不起
- 是我的错
- Sorry.
- My fault.
- 当心我的小牛肉片！
- 去重做一份
- Careful with my piccatas!
- Make another piccata!
去做4号桌的海蜇虾，我来做嫩煎小牛肉片
Do the langoustine for table 4.
I'll do the piccata.
这不是你该做的，催下鸡肉
It's not your job.
Check the chicken.
看啊！鸡肉不够
Look! It's not enough chicken.
你想让杰罗姆被训吗？多加一点
You want Jerome to get yelled at?
Add more.
把这里清理掉，嫩煎小牛肉片马上好
Clean this up, please.
Piccata, now.
当心背后！
Behind you!
做的很好，杰克，在卡古的第一周表现不错
Good work, Jacky.
Nice first week at the Cargo.
谢谢，主厨
Thanks, chef.
拉加德先生！我喜欢你的柠檬鸡！
Mr. Lagarde!
I love your lemon chicken!
但是你应该多用点柠檬
But you should
use more lemon.
你自己可以多加点！
Add it yourself!
对啊，我怎么就没想到呢！
Sure.
I hadn't thought of that!
5分钟后直播
Live in 5 minutes.
我们去哪？
Where are we going?
到布景那，录制我的节目
To the set.
To shoot my show.
不行！我不能做电视节目
No way!
I can't do a TV show.
如果我妻子看见了怎么办？
What if my wife sees?
她在工作，不会看电视的
She works.
She won't be watching TV.
那我的岳父母看见了呢？
What if my in-laws watch?
拍摄的时候能叫我布莱恩吗？
Can you call me Brian
while shooting?
欢迎收看我的节目“亚历山大市场”
Welcome to my show,
"Alexandre's Market".
我很高兴为大家介绍我的新助手
I'm happy to introduce you
to my new assistant.
这位是…
This is...
- 布莱恩
- Brian.
布莱恩，今天我们将要做的是法式烩小牛肉配春季蔬菜
Brian, this week we'll make
veal navarin with spring vegetables.
99年你在于泽斯的旅店时，菜单里的烩小牛肉？
The navarin from your 1999 menu
at the Inn in Uzès?
- 正是
- 棒极了
- Exactly.
- Excellent.
- 如大家所见，杰克…
- 布莱恩
- As you can see, Jacky...
- Brian.
布莱恩是一本鲜活的法式美食字典
Brian is the living memory
of French gastronomy.
- 为什么要带太阳镜？
- 那样就没人能认出他了
- Why the sunglasses?
- So no one recognizes him.
为什么装扮成这样上电视？
Why go on TV in that case?
想…匿名地被大家所认识
To be recognized but... incognito.
将小牛肋部的肉切成大块
We cut the veal flanks
into nice chunks.
同时，我，布莱恩，削好胡萝卜
In the meantime,
I, Brian, peel the carrots.
- 为什么要叫布莱恩？
- 他的美国名字
- Why Brian?
- His American name.
切好香葱
Cut these chives.
什么？你准备用香葱？
What?
You're using chives?
你的食谱用的是龙嵩叶
Your recipe calls
for tarragon!
我们在直播，杰克真爱搞怪
We're shooting live.
Jacky's a real clown.
不是杰克，是布莱恩，而且我很认真
Not Jacky. Brian.
I take your navarin very seriously.
好吧，那就不用香葱
So no chives.
让我们用…
Let's use...
用一些百里香
some thyme!
我们不能用百里香！别随便更改你的拿手菜！
We won't use thyme!
Don't alter your masterpiece!
他们是真的在争吵吗？
Is this a real fight?
- 谢谢，布莱恩，你可以走了
- 我想尝尝这炖小牛肉
- Thanks Brian. You can go.
- I want to taste the navarin.
- 没有香葱或百里香果然更好
- 闭嘴
- Better without chives or thyme.
- Shut up.
女士们先生们，祝好胃口，下星期再见
Ladies and gentlemen, bon appétit.
See you next week.
再多点龙嵩叶或许更好
A bit of tarragon
would have helped.
闭嘴
Shut your trap.
今晚我就做炖小牛肉了
I'm making a navarin tonight.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 以后不要再这样了
- 我保护了你的食谱
- Never again.
- I defended your recipe.
亚历山大，节目真棒
Alexandre, that was wonderful!
你们两个配合真不错
That was some routine, you two!
我重新看了下你的合同
I reread your contract.
我知道该怎么从卡古·拉加德解雇你了
I know how to fire you
from Cargo Lagarde.
如果你失去一个星级
If you lose one star,
你就会被解雇
you're fired.
我永远不会失去的
I'll never lose one.
我认识所有米其林指南的老板
I know all the owners
of the guides.
两个美食评论家就要来卡古·拉加德了
Two critics are going
to Cargo Lagarde soon.
如果不走运…他们正巧不喜欢你的菜肴
Tough luck...
They don't like your cuisine.
你的三星就危险了
I'm not sure you'll keep
your three stars.
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
如果你离开了卡古，你的公寓也就没了
If you lose Cargo,
you lose your apartment.
那是我们的，再见，亚历山大
It's ours.
Bye, Alexandre.
你们两个玩的开心哈！
Have fun you two!
- 振作点，会过去的
- 你在干嘛？
- Chin up. It'll be fine.
- What are you doing?
- 安慰你
- 安慰我？
- Comforting you.
- Comforting me?
因为…
Because...
- 闭嘴，给我回去工作
- 好的，主厨
- Get to work and keep quiet.
- Yes, chef.
再见，主厨
Goodbye, chef.
斯坦尼斯拉斯·马特来找了所有的供应商
Stanislas Matter came
to see all the suppliers.
如果我们再卖给你，他就不从我们这买东西
If we sell to you,
he won't buy from us.
那个混蛋，我该怎么办那？
That bastard. What do I do now?
别担心
Don't worry.
我永远不会忘记你的帮助的，我会帮你
I'll never forget your aid.
I'll help you.
谢谢，马可，你才是真正的朋友！
Thanks, Marco. What a friend!
朱利安！
Julien!
这是朱利安，以后他会做采购
This is Julien.
He'll be doing the shopping for us.
这是马可
This is Marco.
蒂博，过来
Thibault, come here.
在这羊肉酱里加点肉桂和一片荷花叶
Add cinnamon and a lotus
leaf to the lamb sauce.
- 我们不能改他的食谱
- 这是他的创作
- We can't change his recipes.
- They're his creations.
他全权委托给我了
He gave me carte blanche.
- 不行！
- 这样味道会很好
- But I can't!
- It'll be great.
过来
Come here.
- 照他说的做
- 他会被教训的
- Do it.
- He'll be furious!
- 亚历山大会炒了他
- 小滑头
- He'll fire him.
- Little prick.
好注意，我照做
Good idea. I'll do it.
在8号桌有两个客人，看上去像是美食家
I have two people at table 8.
Critics, I think.
只是在品尝
Not eating, just tasting.
他们不停问问题，还点了羊肉
They ask questions.
They ordered the lamb.
然后？
And?
你的副手改了食谱
Your second-in-command
changed the recipe.
什么？
What?
你会付出代价的
You're going to
pay for this.
就是他们
There they are.
东西怎样？
How's everything?
拉加德先生，都很美味
Mr. Lagarde, it's delicious.
我曾经吃过你的羊肉，然后…
I tried your lamb
once before and....
然后？
And?
加点肉桂真是天才的想法
Brilliant idea to have added
cinnamon.
肉桂？
Cinnamon?
我认为肉桂把味道混合的很不错…
I thought the cinnamon might make
for an interesting twist...
里面还有另外一种风味
There's another flavor too.
我一时间尝不出来
I can't put my finger on it.
- 他不会说的
- 对…他不会说的
- He won't say.
- No... he won't say.
- 荷叶，是吗？
- 荷叶，棒极了
- Lotus, right?
- Lotus, bravo.
我喜欢口味上的不同
I like some conflict
in the flavors.
简直美妙
It's crazy.
巴黎的人们对你的评价
What people in Paris
say about you.
“他总是一成不变”
"He repeats himself."
“只是个商人而已”
"Just a businessman."
他们都太刻薄了，你仍然是最好的厨师
They're mean.
You're still the best.
- 最顶尖的！
- 谢谢，谢谢
- Tops!
- Thank you, thank you.
亚历山大…我不知道该不该…
Alexandre... if I may...
我听说米其林指南的美食家
I've heard that critics from Le Guide
在你介绍新菜单的时候会过来
are coming the day you introduce your
new menu.
4月12号，我想是
April 12th, I think.
米其林指南？谢谢你告诉我这些
Le Guide?
Thanks for telling me.
比瑟隆和玛夏尔，他们不喜欢传统菜肴
Busseron and Marchal.
They hate classic cuisine.
如果让我说的话：给他们做点时髦的
If I may be so bold:
make them a molecular dish.
用上液氮，透明的那种
With liquid nitrogen.
Transparent.
- 这是他们喜欢的
- 分子菜肴？
- It's their thing.
- Molecular cuisine?
不行
Not that.
这是怎么回事？
What the hell is this?
肉桂？荷叶？你竟敢改我的食谱？
Cinnamon? Lotus?
You're changing my recipes?
你在东京四季时做菲力牛排用了同样的酱汁
You served the same sauce
with filet mignon
都有肉桂！
at the Tokyo Four Seasons.
It had cinnamon!
你不能拿羊肉和野味比较！
But you can't compare lamb
and venison!
我只是在诠释你的创作
I was interpreting you.
我把新的亚历山大料理和旧的亚历山大酱料配合在了一起
I tied a new Alexandre dish
to an old Alexandre sauce.
亚历山大说了，别在
Alexandre says to stop
making connections
亚历山大和亚历山大之间做任何的联系了！懂吗？
between Alexandre and
Alexandre! Understand?
不好意思，但是我知道亚历山大是怎么样的
Excuse me,
but I know how Alexandre works.
- 但是我就是亚历山大！
- 那又如何？有什么关系吗？
- But I'm Alexandre!
- So? How does that matter?
我从一开始就跟随着亚历山大
I've followed Alexandre
since day one.
你想听真相吗？
You want the truth?
在夏洛特离开前，亚历山大比现在好多了
Alexandre was better
before Charlotte left.
夏洛特？
Charlotte?
我的前期？干嘛把她扯进来？
My ex-wife?
Why drag her into this?
自从她离开后，你的酱料就停滞不前了
Since she left,
your sauces are stagnant.
没人这么说过
No one says it,
但是…你的酱料遇到瓶颈了
but...
you're in a sauce rut.
别扯夏洛特
Leave Charlotte out
of my veal stock!
就这样吧，我受够了
This is over.
I'm fed up.
- 你走吧！
- 什么？你要解雇我？
- Get lost!
- What? You're firing me?
是的！试用结束了
Yes!
End of apprenticeship.
好吧…
Okay...
没问题
No problem.
想要杂碎和扇贝的灵感吗？
Want inspiration
for sweetbread and scallops?
我知道亚历山大会怎么做
I know what Alexandre
would have done.
食谱是我设计的！
I do the creating here!
再见，拉加德先生
Goodbye, Mr. Lagarde.
- 继续工作！
- 是，主厨！
- Keep scrubbing!
- Yes, chef!
波诺先生？
Mr. Bonnot?
主厨想问你，亚历山大会怎么做杂碎？
Chef asks how Alexandre
would do the sweetbread.
用接骨木醋溶解肉粒
Deglazed, with elderberry vinegar.
溶化，接骨木
Deglazed, elderberry.
他想让你回去
He wants you to come.
也不算很快嘛
Not too soon.
加接骨木醋
The elderberry vinegar now.
干嘛笑的这么傻？
Why the dumb smile?
这是我第一次被重新雇用
The first time
I've ever been rehired.
尝下
Go on.
- 你是对的，你个笨蛋
- 当然
- You're right, you idiot.
- You bet.
好吧…
Okay...
我们会一起做这个菜单，但是…
We'll do the menu
together, but...
你也是一个笨蛋！
You can be
a real dipshit too!
对不起，亚历山大…我在讲电话
I'm sorry, Alexandre...
I'm on the phone.
常，蝴蝶结面是有嚼劲的，你煮过头了！
Chang, farfalle are done al dente.
Yours are overcooked!
好吧，我不知道
Okay. I didn't know.
重新来过，煮9分钟
Start over.
Let it boil 9 minutes.
记住，不停的搅拌…
And remember,
stir, stir, stir...
- 这是什么？
- 我在帮养老院
- What's this?
- I'm helping at the old-age home.
你在同时做两份工作
So at lunch
you were working both jobs?
那些老人喜欢我的菜，我不能就这么放手
The residents love my recipes.
I couldn't just vanish.
我不想惹麻烦
I come in peace.
I want no trouble.
我只是让西里尔和他的装潢师参观我的餐厅
I'm just showing my restaurant
to Cyril and his decorator.
离开我的厨房
Leave my kitchen.
好吧
Very well.
这是拉维尼先生，法院执行官
This is Mr. Laveine, court bailiff.
他会告诉你我可以参观我的餐厅
He'll tell you I can visit
without danger, my restaurant
并重建
to have it redone.
当然，如果你失去一颗星的话
If you lose a star.
Of course.
- 这些都不要吗，马特先生？
- 对，所有的
- This goes, Mr. Matter?
- All of it.
那里要放抛光的陶瓷
And that will be
polished ceramic.
敲掉墙，让空间大点
Lose the wall, open it up.
客人们在这里吃饭
The customers eat
here and there.
这里我想要一个大的台屏
Here I want
a large table-screen.
扇贝？好主意
Scallops?
Good idea.
想从它里面找到食谱？
Find the recipe in Elle?
看来我掌管卡古只是时间问题了
It's about time
I see to the Cargo.
西里尔，跟我走
So, Cyril, come with me.
来看看冷库
Come see the
winter garden.
我们要拆掉这些门，我们需要空间
We'll lose the doors.
We need space.
太过时了！
Too old-fashioned!
- 你会失去一颗星？
- 有可能
- Can you lose a star?
- It can happen.
回去工作
Let's get back to work.
杰克！我把柠檬酱烧糊了
Jacky!
I burnt the lemon sauce.
另找个锅子重新开始
Get another pan
and start over.
比阿特丽斯刚打电话来，她没找=到你
Beatrice called here.
She couldn't reach you.
她想给你看点婴儿用品
She has baby stuff
to show you.
是吗？我会打她电话的
Oh yeah?
I'll call her back.
我在找杰克
I'm looking for Jacky.
他不久前辞职了
He quit here a while ago.
真的？
Really?
- 去问问厨房吧
- 厨房？
- Go ask in the kitchen.
- The kitchen?
首先，让大豆浸泡在柠檬…
First, let the soy beans
marinate in the lemon...
有人告诉我说我能在这找到杰克
I was told I'd
find Jacky here.
他辞职了，找他干嘛？
He quit.
What's it about?
- 他在哪？
- 别告诉他妻子！
- Where is he?
- Don't tell his wife!
在屏幕上
On the screen.
- 你是？
- 他的妻子
- And you are...?
- His wife.
她要过来了？那我们得当心点
She's coming?
So we better watch out.
- 我就是她的妻子
- 噢…完了
- I'm his wife.
- Oh... shit.
你是怎么告诉比阿特丽斯的？
What did you tell Beatrice?
我和她说了你的小三
About your hookers.
关掉
Cut it out.
我说你有事出去了10分钟
I said you had
10 minutes of errands to do.
你是笨蛋吗？我怎么在10分钟内回来？
Are you stupid?
How do I get back there now?
我得找个理由打给她了！
I have to call her
and find an excuse!
杰克当心!
Jacky watch out!
等下
Just a sec.
我妻子的铃声也是这样的
My wife has the
same ringtone.
- 嘿，亲爱的…
- 怎么了？
- Hey, baby...
- Yeah?
- 你还好吗？
- 当然
- You okay?
- Yeah.
我就是想告诉你别来我工作的地方了
I'm just calling to say
don't bother coming by work.
我这堵车去不了了
I won't make it.
I'm stuck in traffic.
- 在哪？
- 民族广场附近
- Where?
- Not even that far... By Nation.
我也在附近，你在哪？
I'm near Nation too.
Where exactly?
你看不到我的，我在左边…
You can't see me.
I'm on the left...
在几辆卡车后面
stuck behind
some trucks.
等等，走啊！
Hold on. Move!
我也要去工作！让我过去！
I have to work too!
Let me through!
对不起…我开始走了
I'm sorry...
It's starting to move.
我在伏尔泰大道上了，我听到了回音？
I'm at Boulevard Voltaire.
I hear an echo.
你怎么在那？
Why do I see
you there?
- 你在哪？
- 杰克，你妻子在这
- Where are you?
- Jacky, your wife's here.
- 为什么这样做？
- 什么？我什么都没做啊
- Why do this?
- Do what? I did nothing.
很好，你把我当成个白痴
Right.
You think I'm an idiot.
- 我受够了， 我们玩完了
- 比阿特丽斯，等等！
- I'm sick of this. It's over.
- Beatrice, wait!
听着！常，做点什么！
Listen!
Chang, do something!
- 他没去找妓女！
- 不是那个！
- He didn't go to see hookers!
- Not that!
亲爱的，听我解释，你不能就这样离开了
Honey, listen to me.
You can't leave like this!
你麻烦大了
You're in deep shit.
你的手下真是个笨蛋
Your boy's a real champ.
有他在就不愁降星级了
With him it'll be
shooting stars.
他们经过，只是不停留而已
They pass by.
They don't stay.
他们只是路过
They just shoot on by.
再见了，三星级
So long, stars.
还是自动录音
Answering machine again.
她不在家
She's not home.
别打了，这没用的
Stop calling.
It won't get her back.
我欺骗了她，她永远不会原谅我了
That's not it. I lied to her.
She'll never forgive me.
- 我知道
- 他们都一样
- I know her.
- They're all the same.
她们想要嫁个好男人，但是只要一搞砸…
They want to marry a great man
but at the first screw up...
她们就离开了
they're gone.
你知道吗？
You know what?
她提过很多次想要结婚
She mentioned marriage a lot
但是每次我就像个白痴一样说：“还没到时候”
and each time like an idiot
I said "not now".
那么，你觉得如何？
So?
What do you think?
- 这很顺口
- 是啊
- It's flat.
- Yeah.
你有尝过白马庄园的葡萄酒吗？
Have you ever tasted
a Cheval Blanc?
没
Nope.
61年的白马庄园
Cheval Blanc '61 .
太棒了
Just wonderful.
接骨木醋先生，他毕竟不是全知全能的
He doesn't know everything,
Mr. Elderberry Vinegar.
尝尝这个
Taste this.
看这色泽
Check out the color.
闻闻这酒香
Smell that bouquet.
简直让我落泪，白马庄园
It brings tears to my eyes,
a Cheval Blanc.
我也是
Me too.
我快热泪盈眶了
My eyes are welling up.
美食家4天后就来了
The critics come in 4 days.
我完蛋了
I'm cooked.
干嘛这样说？会有机会的
Why do you say that?
It'll be another triumph.
他们是分子菜肴的死忠
They're disciples
of molecular cuisine.
- 分子菜肴？
- 再见了，三星级
- Molecular cuisine?
- Goodbye, 3rd star.
尝过柏图斯的酒吗？
Ever tasted a Petrus?
没有
Neither.
- 那白马酒庄呢？
- 以后再喝吧
- And the Cheval Blanc?
- Later!
有了
I've got it!
我认识些人
I know someone.
一位西班牙的新式菜肴专家
A Spanish specialist
in miocailulaire cuisine.
他是最棒的
He's our man. The best.
他有名吗？
Is he well-known?
有人说他是个天才
I was told he's a genius.
我来打给他，胡安·卡斯提拉
I'll call him.
Juan Castella.
我还有他的号码
I still have his number.
自动留言
Answering machine.
嗨，胡安，我是杰克·波诺
Hello, Juan.
This is Jacky Bonnot.
我现在和亚历山大·拉加德一起工作
I'm working now
with Mr. Alexandre Lagarde.
我们需要你
I think we need your skills.
尽快回我电话
Call me back.
'As fastas as possiblo'.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
谢谢你为我做的一切
Thank you for what
you're doing for me.
这是我的荣幸
It's an honor.
如果我能保住三星
If ever I keep the
three stars,
你就是副主管了
you'll be
second-in-command.
真的？
Really?
- 我更喜欢…
- 握手
- I'd prefer...
- Shake.
“左右手”
..."right-hand man."
“第一助理”也不错
"First assistant"
isn't bad either.
好吧，第一助理
Okay, first assistant.
“代理主厨”是不是更好？听起来…
Is "deputy chef" better?
It sounds...
- 你到底想不想握手了？
- 对不起
- Will you shake?
- Sorry.
- 来点白兰地吧
- 当然！
- Let's have some Armagnac.
- Sure!
她在纳维尔！
She's in Nevers!
我要像她求婚
I'll go ask her
to marry me.
比阿特丽斯在纳维尔她爸妈那
Beatrice went to her
parents house in Nevers.
我要走了
I'm abandoning you.
我不能没有她
I can't live without her.
我理解
I understand.
我送你过去
Let me drive you there.
那么…
So...
首先，告诉她我们已经有合同了
first, tell her
we're signing a contract.
我会安排的
I'll manage.
我过去和她谈，她会进我的怀抱的
I go, I talk,
she falls into in my arms.
开个玩笑
Just kidding.
我会帮你做好铺垫的
I'll just pave the way.
好地方，纳维尔
Neat place, Nevers!
就在这…前面右转
It's here...
Turn up ahead.
如果他们不在家，那就肯定在这
If they're not home,
they're here.
走
Let's go.
这边
This way.
她在那
That's her.
她太美了
But she's beautiful!
嘘！
Duh!
跟着我
Follow me.
什么？
What?
我没有戒指！
I don't have a ring!
- 我们不能空着手去
- 我该怎么办？
- We can't go empty-handed.
- What do I do?
我会做些她喜欢的东西，她会原谅我的
I'll whip up something she likes.
She'll forgive me.
去掉这些…然后…
Get rid of this... Next...
杰克，你在这干嘛？
Jacky, why are you here?
嗨，卡罗尔
Hello, Carole.
我想给比阿特丽斯一个惊喜，拜托别告诉她
It's a surprise for Beatrice.
Please don't say a word.
就当在家里一样
You're at home here.
这是亚历山大·拉加德
This is Alexandre Lagarde.
亚历山大，这是卡罗尔，这里的主人
Alexandre, Carole, the owner.
拉加德先生…真是荣幸
Mr. Lagarde... it's an honor.
是我的荣幸
The honor is mine.
真巧，我的厨师下个月就要离开了
What a coincidence.
My cook leaves next month.
你愿意的话，可以试用下我
If you want,
you can take me on a trial basis.
我可付不起你工资
You're too pricey for me.
我们是为了比阿特丽斯来这的！
Didn't we come
for Beatrice?
对…比阿特丽斯，对…
Yes... Beatrice, yes...
对不起，打扰了
Sorry to intrude.
我先介绍下我自己…
Let me introduce myself....
你是亚历山大·拉加德
You're Alexandre Lagarde.
对，就是我
That's right.
That's me.
比阿特丽斯，听着
Beatrice, listen,
我来这是想告诉你，都是我的错…
I'm here to say
it's all my fault...
是我造成了现在这局面
I brought about
this situation.
谢谢你能过来，但是我知道这不是因为你
Thanks for coming.
But I know it's not you.
告诉杰克我不会见他的
Tell Jacky I won't see him.
别这样说，他想告诉你些东西
Don't say that.
He has to tell you something.
我不想听！
I won't listen!
我想告诉你，如果一切顺利的话
I have to tell you
that if all goes well,
他会在卡古·拉加德全职工作
he'll work full-time
at Cargo Lagarde.
他想雇用杰克！
He wants to hire Jacky!
就要当爸爸的人不应该撒谎
A future father mustn't lie.
他太不负责任了
He's irresponsible.
- 这是事实
- 而且令人难以忍受！
- That's true.
- And unbearable!
是的，我也解雇过他
True. I even fired him.
你不是应该帮我说好话的吗？
Weren't you supposed
to defend me?
你在这干嘛？
Why are you here?
嗨，阿曼德…嗨，玛蒂尔德
Hello, Armand...
Hello, Mathilde.
亲爱的，对不起，求你原谅我
Honey, I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
看看我做了什么
Look what I made.
你最喜欢的焦糖千层派
Your favorite.
Caramel mille-feuille,
小草莓，红浆果
tiny strawberries,
redcurrants,
- 小阿月浑子…
- 我不想要
tiny pistachios...
- I don't want it.
你喜欢的！看啊！
You do! Look!
我还做了一个香草甜心，知道为什么吗？
I made you a vanilla sugar heart.
Know why?
我爱你
I love you.
香草糖也没用！
Vanilla sugar won't work!
由你父母见证
Let me make of the most
of your parents presence
我郑重的问你
to ask you solemnly
愿意嫁给我吗？
if you'll marry me.
不是这样子的！现在不行！
Not like this!
Not now!
- 为什么不？
- 你欺骗了我！
- Why not?
- You lied to me!
好吧，我是欺骗了你，不是什么大不了的
Okay, I lied to you. No big deal.
我从来没有撒过谎
I never lied before.
一次，但是那不算
Once.
But that didn't count.
我们还没真正在一起
We weren't
really together.
我不认为这是个求婚的好时机
I don't think it's
time to propose.
- 我们该走了
- 好吧，我们走
- We should be going.
- Sure, let's go.
我知道这不是好时机…
I know it's not
the right time...
我该怎么阻止蜜饯沉入面饼？
How do I stop candied fruit
from sinking into the batter?
把蜜饯加在面糊上不停的鞭打
Add the fruit to whipped batter
and keep on beating.
谢谢，拉加德先生
Thank you, Mr. Lagarde.
还有个办法
There's another school.
把面糊放进冰箱
Put the batter in the fridge
and the next day,
到第二天就可以直接放蜜饯了…
just add the
candied fruit...
- 搞定了吗？
- 晚安，卡罗尔
- So did it work?
- Goodnight, Carole.
没事的，她爱他
It's all fine.
She loves him.
- 你叫卡罗尔？
- 是的
- Your name is Carole?
- That's right.
- 我叫亚历山大
- 我知道
- I'm Alexandre.
- I know.
- 我会考虑你的提议的
- 当然
- I may accept that offer.
- Of course.
再见
See you soon.
她真美
She's pretty.
我知道
I know.
不是比阿特丽斯，是卡罗尔
Not Beatrice. Carole.
我是说…她们都很漂亮
I mean...
they're both pretty.
但是卡罗尔…
But Carole...
你脸上有奶油
You have cream on you.
果仁糖不够
Not even enough praline.
别客气
Make yourself at home.
这个金帽子，是你的第一个奖品
The Toque d'Or,
your first trophy.
这是…
And this is the...
晚安，明天见
Good night.
See you tomorrow.
嘿，宝贝
Hey, baby.
还是我
It's me again.
我知道我不应该再打了…
I know I should
stop calling...
但是我做不到
but I can't.
所以…回个电话好吗？
So... call me back.
- 还在学习？
- 我得好好准备
- Still working?
- I have to be ready.
这次我要失去一颗星了
This time I'm going
to lose a star.
二星，三星，没什么区别
2, 3, same thing.
来看我答辩吧
But come for my thesis.
我就要失去三星了你还在扯那些没人读的俄国书
I may lose a star and you blab on
about Russian books no one reads.
去告诉大家
Go tell the rest
of the world,
以后再也没有松露摊鸡蛋吃了
no more scrambled
eggs with truffles.
看他们会不会哭
See how they cry.
- 你怎么变得这么自私？
- 你教我的
- How can you be so selfish?
- You taught me.
我是很少陪你，但是我让很多人感到快乐
I was never around.
But I made lots of people happy.
是的，其他人
Yeah, other people.
你永远只关心你的餐厅
It's always about
your restaurants.
我不打扰你了
I'll let you work.
我才不管你
I don't care.
除了在养老院工作
Besides working
at the Home,
我看不出他们有任何资质
I don't see how
they're qualified.
常在疯马乐队做过化妆，穆萨开过卡车
Chang did make-up at Crazy Horse.
Moussa drove trucks.
提提过去是铺瓷砖的
And Titi used to lay tiles.
我该让他们干嘛？
What should I
do with them?
我们需要员工
We need a crew here.
以及试验样品的小白鼠
And guinea pigs to try
the first samples.
有医疗保险吗？
Got health coverage?
就是他了，我去开门
That's him.
I'll go answer.
亚历山大，这是胡安·卡斯特拉
Alexandre,
this is Juan Castella,
世界闻名的专家…
world-famous
specialist...
- 我可以说“世界闻名”吗？
- 当然
- Can I say "world-famous"?
- You can.
…在分子菜肴方面
...in molecular cuisine.
你好
Good day,
亚历山大·拉加德先生，很荣幸能见到你
Señor Alejandro Lagarde.
I am very honored.
我也是
So am I.
首先
First of all,
我想尝下你的“料理”
I will taste your "cousin-e".
我的表兄弟？
My cousin?
这是什么？
What is it?
海藻牛肉
Beef with seaweed
a surf and turf.
很不错，拉加德先生
Straight to problem,
Señor Lagarde.
让我们开始吧
Let's get to work.
处理下它们
Pluck them.
你从哪里弄到的？
Where did you get them?
野鸭，巴黎边上的树林里
Wild ducks.
From woods near Paris.
巴黎边上的树林？
Woods near Paris?
去处理下，现在
Pluck them.
Now.
还要鸭肉？
More duck?
要的，再加
More, more.
再加，多加点
Much more, much more.
要加足够多的鸭肉才能获得其中的精华
看什么看，快点工作！
很好，看
I am happy.
Look.
鸭肉在哪？
Where are the ducks?
我提取了鸭肉的精华
I undertook fragmentation
of duck
然后将味道还原进了这小方块中
and reconstituted taste,
into little cube.
我要吃这个？
I should serve this?
他还没完成，现在他要…
He's not finished.
Now he'll work on...
用色彩装饰下
Artistic aspect.
The color.
酱料，脆度
The sauces.
The crunchiness.
穆萨，提提，常！
Moussa, Titi, Chang!
过来下
Come have a look.
你们三个能不能…
Can you three...
尝下这个？
- 鸭肉配柑橘苏打
taste this?
- Duck with quince cracker.
- 哪里？
- 那儿
- Where?
- There.
- 那些奶酪块？
- 鸭肉配柑橘饼干
- The cheese cubes?
- Duck and quince cracker.
柑橘和鸭子？
Quince and quacker?
你在那些小块里放了柑橘？
You put the quacking
in the cube?
你怎么做到的？
How did you do it?
别废话，快尝尝
It's time to taste it.
- 这样子正常吗？
- 我要记录下
- Is that normal?
- I take notes.
太多液氮了，要减少15克
Too much liquid nitrogen.
Reduce by 15 grams.
- 要我们停下吗？
- 还不行，继续
- Should we stop chewing?
- Not yet. Continue.
怎样？
So?
好像有只粉末的鸭子在里面成型
It's like a powdered duck
that takes shape inside.
有鱼肉的味道
It tastes fishy.
是的，你把鱼和鸭做一起了！
It's true.
You made fish with duck!
应该是冷凝器的问题
Must be problem
with condenser.
我得检查下
I have to go check.
尝一下，拉加德先生
Taste, Señor Lagarde.
鸭肉的精华
The true essence of duck.
没有啊，这味道是…树莓
Not at all.
lt's... raspberry.
继续…继续尝
Continue...
Continue eating.
这是怎么回事？
What the hell?
别担心，拉加德先生，正常的化学反应
Don't worry, Señor Lagarde.
Normal chemical reaction.
正常是什么意思？
What do you mean, normal?
够了！
Enough bullshit!
不想再试试其他神奇的食物了？
So no more magic food?
不，够了！
No, no more magic food!
你太敏感了！
You, very hypersensitive.
我这就走！
Me leave!
这就对了，再见
That's right.
Goodbye!
我受够了，别再让我看见这些东西！
I've had enough.
No more ducks in cubes!
20年来的这些压力只是为了取悦三个美食家！
20 years of pressure
just to please three critics!
我不干了
I'm calling it quits.
你答应给我一份工作的
You promised me
a job contract.
我们只有两天来开发这份见鬼的菜单！
We have two days to invent a menu
that's still a mystery!
这不可能做到！
It's not possible!
那西里尔·博斯呢？他一直处理的很好
And Cyril Boss?
He manages fine.
他是怎么做到的？
How does he do it?
我们怎么不去那尝尝？
Why don't we
go eat there?
我们可以知道…
We'll check it out...
我们品尝，学习，分析…
we'll taste, understand, analyze...
- 然后我们改造下
- 所有人都认识我
- And we reinvent.
- Everyone knows me.
我打过去说：“拉加德要订两个位置”？
I call and say:
"Table for two for Lagarde"?
“晚餐吗？”“不，来做间谍！”
"For dinner?"
"No, for spying!"
不可能
Nonsense.
- 没别的办法了？
- 我想不出来
- There's no solution?
- I don't see one.
- 主厨？
- 怎么？
- Chef?
- What?
常…过去是个化妆师
Chang...
He was a make-up artist.
那又如何？
And?
野武士先生，夫人
Mr. and Mrs. Nobushi.
我们很荣幸能服务你们呢
We're honored
to welcome the cultural attaché.
今晚我们有新菜单
Tonight we have
our new menu.
请…
This way...
主厨西里尔·博斯欢迎你们
The chef Cyril Boss
welcomes you.
想象一下…
Imagine...
- 他们会把卡古·拉加德变成这样
- 灾难
- They'll do this to Cargo Lagarde.
- Disaster.
请坐，祝您用餐愉快
Your table.
Enjoy your evening.
主厨西里尔·博斯向您推荐他的交响乐菜单
The chef Cyril Boss
proposes his Symphonic Menu.
液氮香槟
Liquid nitrogen champagne.
这是什么？
What is this thing?
尝起来如何？
How does it taste?
香槟和雪茄汁
Champagne with cigar juice
浓缩的家禽乌冬面
Compression of fowl
with udon noodles?
磷光萝卜慕斯
Phosphorescent radish mousse.
- 杂碎意大利面
- 虚拟鱿鱼
- Sweetbread spaghetti.
- Virtual calamari.
我们也该用虚拟的方式吃？
Do you eat it virtually too?
请试试这些酒，波美侯的精华
Please try some wine.
Essence of Pomerol.
没有酒
Without wine.
没有葡萄
No grapes,
没有酒精
no alcohol.
那里面有什么？
What's in it then?
这个不能说
We can't say.
相当神秘！
Very, very mysterious!
我喜欢
Mizuko likes to be silly.
我会将它放在冰块里
I'll keep it on ice.
谁会想喝没有酒精的酒？
Who wants non-alcoholic wine?
口感很木
It's woody.
我尝到了波美侯的感觉
I taste the
idea of Pomerol.
- 还有红浆果
- 以及皮革
- And redcurrant.
- And leather.
我尝到了皮革的味道
I taste leather.
羊奶酪和当季水果
Sheep milk cheese
with seasonal fruits.
番茄金枪鱼腹
Tuna belly
with tomato.
焦糖韭葱配柠檬香茅
Caramelized leek
with lemon grass.
这是…
What the...
牛肉和小牛肉
Beef and veal
in their garden.
吃牛肉的时候闻闻这个
Sniff these
while biting into your beef.
不太实用啊
Not practical.
拿着
You have to take it.
还是不实用
Not practical either.
西里尔·博斯祝您用餐愉快
Cyril Boss wishes
you bon appétit.
我不理解
I can't get it.
这很有趣
This is interesting.
这好苦
It's bitter.
杂碎
Sweetbreads.
杂碎意大利面
Sweetbread spaghetti.
我们可以学这个
We have to copy this.
晚上好，阁下…
Your Excellency...
- 东西如何？
- 我妻子很喜欢
- Enjoying it?
- Wife like lots.
是的…相当喜欢
Yes... very much
不好意思，阁下…
Excuse me,
Excellency...
你们之前也来过吧？
You've eaten
here before!
第一次
First time.
我觉得我好像见过你
I feel as if I've
seen you before.
第一次
First time.
我们从…很远的地方过来
We to come... very far.
大阪，神户，东京，京都，北海道
Osaka, Kobe,
Tokyo, Kyoto, Hokkaido.
我想我应该见过你
I'm sure I've
seen your face.
你是美食餐厅的粉丝吗？
Are you fans of
gastronomic dining?
我们很喜欢…好的餐厅
We to love very much...
fine dining.
你们去过哪？
Where do you go?
杜卡斯
Ducasse.
候布匈，加涅尔
Robuchon.
Gagnaire.
亚历山大·拉加德
Alexandre Lagarde.
他太差劲了！
He totally sucks!
你错了
You wrong.
我们在卡古·拉加德吃的很满意
We to eat very well
at Cargo Lagarde.
别这样…就我们之间说说…
Come on...
Between us...
拉加德还在做炖牛肉
Lagarde still makes
beef stew.
还有，我告诉你一个秘密
What's more
- I'll tell you a secret -
他雇用了一个助手
he hired an
assistant,
一个卖希腊烤肉的笨蛋
a bum who used
to sell gyros.
烤肉男孩！彻底的失败者！
Shish kebab boy!
A total loser!
够了，你应该放尊重一点
You enough.
No respect.
在日本，拉加德先生的餐厅是最好的
In Japan, Monsieur Lagarde
restaurant ichiban!
- 你太过分了
- 是最好的
- Great insult.
- Number one!
你，西里尔·博斯…
You, Cyril Boss...
屁都不算！
nothing at all!
美食家想见见你
The food critics
want to see you.
好的，我马上到，我一会回来
Okay. I'm coming.
I'll be right back.
可能又想要称赞我了
Probably for some
more compliments.
我们最好走吧，不然我都想打他了
We better go or
I'll clobber him.
- 冲脸打
- 走吧
- In the face.
- Let's go.
等下，首先，我们该带走些原料
Wait. First, let's borrow
a few ingredients.
跳的真不错！
Very nice digestive dance!
- 很顺利
- 我身上装满了
- It went well.
- I'm loaded.
这就走了？不想试试试管里的草莓小饼干了？
Leaving?
No strawberry éclair in a test tube?
- 不了，我们走了
- 是的，身体不舒服
- No, we go.
- Yes, sick.
我们会在卡古·拉加德再见的
I'll see you soon
at Cargo Lagarde.
我马上就是那里的主厨了
I'm the new chef there.
如果你再提一次卡古·拉加德
If you mention Cargo
Lagarde again,
你知道我把你的试管放哪了吗？
know where I put
your test tubes?
- 不知道
- 最好不知道
- No.
- Better you don't know.
主厨西里尔·博斯感谢您的光临
The chef Cyril Boss
thanks you for coming.
把东西拿上来
Bring in the food.
葱姜牛肉
Explosion of beef
with ginger!
干嘛叫这么响？
Why are you screaming?
因为有气派
Because it's classier.
没人在三星餐厅里大叫
No one screams
in 3-star restaurants.
我怎么知道？
How would I know?
鱿鱼墨配骨髓吐司
Bone marrow on toast,
vitrified in squid ink.
别大喊
Don't scream.
- 但是提提告诉我说…
- 提提搞错了
- But Titi told me to.
- Titi got it all wrong.
那我也不用叫喽？
So I don't scream either?
- 番茄黄瓜沫
- 什么？
- Tomato and cucumber in their froth.
- What?
番茄黄瓜沫
Tomato and cucumber
in their froth.
谢谢
Thank you.
我说的很轻声了
I said it softly.
怎样，主厨？
So, chef?
- 还好
- 还好？
- It's not bad.
- Not bad?
- 我才睡了4个小时就被吵醒了
- 亲爱的，对不起
- I wake up in 4 hours.
- Honey, I'm sorry.
这是春季菜单，明天有美食评论家过来
It's the Spring Menu.
I have the critics tomorrow.
明天？你不来了吗？
Tomorrow.
You're not coming?
哪？
Where?
看什么看！
Behave yourselves!
把剩下的送上来
Send in the rest.
- 谢谢
- 杰克是对的
- Thank you.
- Jacky's right.
他的办法比拉加德的更好
His method is better
than Lagarde's.
水果分布很均匀！
Fruit in every bite!
别再生他气了，他是个好厨师
Stop making that kid suffer.
He's such a good cook.
他开了200公里
He drove 200 kilometers
来像你求婚
to ask your hand
in marriage.
看看这个蛋糕
Admire the elegance
of this cake.
我对他太过分了吗？
I was too tough on him?
说实话…
Honestly...
怎么了？
What is it?
我要生了
Please take me
to the clinic.
马上，亲爱的
Right away, honey.
等我拿块蛋糕
I'll take a slice
for the ride.
干嘛不拿两块呢？
Why not two?
我来了…
I'm coming...
阿曼丁？
Amandine?
安静，我女儿在睡觉！
Quiet, my daughter
is sleeping!
别擦着墙走！
Don't scuff the walls!
我可以拿
I'll get it.
没事，我能帮你…
No, I'll help you...
那是最后一个了，我马上来
That's the last of it. I'll climb in.
快点，别迟到了
Hurry.
Don't be late.
你不去吗？
You're not coming?
你是对的
You're the one
who's right.
失去爱，我们一无是处
Without love,
we're nothing.
我该怎么做？
What do I do?
你怎么在这？
Why are you here?
你不能饿着肚子去答辩！
You can't take a test
on an empty stomach!
我给你做了杯相当浓的热巧克力
I made you a very intense
hot chocolate.
左下，我会给你弄好的
Sit down. I'll serve you.
记得吗？我们叫这“阿曼丁奶油”
Remember?
We called it "brioche à l'Amandine".
每次考试你都会给我做
You'd make me one
for every exam.
那时候我为了快乐而做饭
Back then I cooked
for pleasure.
然后我就只想着我的三星餐厅
Then I became the guy
with all the 3-star restaurants.
我忘记了我的最爱
I forgot what I loved most.
你…和烹饪
You and... cooking.
他们呢？
Where are they?
我得看你给考官们讲巴尔扎克抄袭哥萨克人
I must see you tell the jury
Balzac stole from Cossaks
写成了“驴皮记”
for "The Magic Skin".
你读了我的论文？
You read my thesis?
- 你读了我的论文？
- 快吃
- You read my thesis?
- Eat.
你看过了？
You read it?
三星级的
Three stars.
怎么了？怎么什么都没有？
What's wrong?
Why is nothing ready?
马可不卖东西给我们了
Marco stopped selling to us.
太晚了，只剩蔫掉的蔬菜了
It was too late.
Just wilted vegetables.
你连对话都做不到的那种…
The kind...
you can't whisper to.
什么？
What?
我找亚历山大
I'm looking for Alexandre.
他不在，他要晚点来
He's not here.
He'll be here later.
可以让他打电话给我吗？
Will you tell him to call me?
你想跟着我做吗？
Would you like
to work with me?
不了，谢谢，亚历山大信任我，所以我…
No thank you.
Alexandre trusts me, and I'd...
你太穷了，杰克，为自己考虑下
You're too pure, Jacky.
Think about yourself.
亚历山大顽固守旧
Alexandre insists on living
in a bygone era.
我不这么认为
I don't agree at all.
他仍然是最好的，我会是他的副手
He's still the best.
And I'll be second-in-command.
如果他保得住他的三星
If he keeps his three stars.
但是，他人不在，又没东西，你能做什么？
But what will you do without him
and nothing to cook?
焗芝士？
Grilled cheese?
你高估自己了，你肯定会失败的
You overestimate yourself.
You can only fail.
或许吧，但是我还是想试一下
Maybe.
But I want to try.
试什么？
Try what?
你以为你会学着食谱做菜就是个主厨了？
You think you're a chef
because you follow recipes?
你才不是！你只不过是个业余的！
You're not!
You're an amateur!
这里是专业的地方
And this place is
for professionals.
你有发明过什么吗?
Have you ever
invented something?
鸡蛋含羞草还是提拉米苏?
Eggs mimosa or tiramisu?
这些是你创的吗?
Was that you?
你只是个模仿者而已
You're a copycat.
只是个唱卡拉OK的家伙
Just a guy who
sings karaoke.
仅此而已
That's all.
所以,回家去吧…
So go home...
波诺先生
Mr. Bonnot.
好吧…
Okay...
我们该怎么办？
What do we do?
什么都不做
Nothing.
没有蔬菜，没有灵感，没有亚历山大
No vegetables, no ideas,
no Alexandre.
- 还有我们
- 很好，但又能如何？
- We're here.
- That's nice, but so what?
斯坦尼斯拉斯是对的
Stanislas is right.
我只会模仿，我应该做我的油漆匠的
I just sing karaoke.
I should have stayed a painter.
比阿特丽斯也就不会离开我了
Beatrice would
never have left.
- 我要去找她
- 什么？
- I'll go find her.
- What?
就这样了？
Is that all?
我们为了你放弃了工作然而你却自己放弃了
We left our jobs for you
and you bail.
- 你会让我们失业的
- 你答应过我们
- You'll put us on unemployment.
- You promised us.
对不起
I'm sorry.
那家伙说对了，你确实不专业
That guy was right.
You're not professional.
你只是为了快乐而做菜
You cook for pleasure.
专业的厨师是为了其他东西
Professionals do
it for others.
我铺瓷砖可不是为了取乐
I wasn't laying
tiles for pleasure,
但是地面因为我而平整
but so people's
floors were even.
电话，先生
Phone call, sir.
- 亚历山大？
- 不是，一个女的
- Alexandre?
- No, a woman.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 是我
- 亲爱的…
- It's me.
- Oh baby...
真高兴能听到你的声音
I'm happy to
hear from you.
我对自己太失望了
I'm so upset with myself.
我欺骗了你，而且一无所获，我不该这样做的
I lied and I shouldn't have.
And for nothing.
- 我们搞砸了
- 怎么会？
- We got screwed.
- How so?
美食评论家在这，但是我们连材料都没
Critics are here and
we have no food.
我相信你可以做好的，你最会做这种东西
I'm sure it'll be fine.
It's how you cook best.
这次真的是什么都没有
This time there's
really nothing.
我放弃了，我算是知道了
I'm calling it quits.
Now I know.
烹饪不是我该做的
Cooking is not for me.
这些只是借口！就拼一下又如何
You and your excuses!
Go all the way for once.
不然你怎么知道自己的价值在哪？
How else can you
know your worth?
你给我做的料理都那么棒
What you cook for
me is so amazing.
你能行的
Your saving grace.
那是因为我爱你
Obviously for you
it was because I love you.
就想象你是在为我做菜
Imagine you're
cooking for me.
还有你女儿
And your daughter.
真的？
Really?
我有女儿了？
I have a daughter?
我就过来！
I'm coming.
先做完你该做的
Finish what you
have to do first.
你确定？
Are you sure?
别担心，我们等你
Don't worry.
We're waiting.
再见
See you soon.
附近有超市吗？
Is there
a supermarket nearby?
街角有个食品杂货店
Just a grocery
at the corner.
做好准备
Start getting ready.
把炉子热起来
Turn on the stoves.
提提，烧水，穆萨，常，我们走
Titi, boil water.
Moussa, Chang, let's go.
一起来
Come with me too.
你们也一起来
You there, come along.
伙计们…我做爸爸了！
Guys... I'm a daddy.
我做爸爸了！
I'm a daddy!
有蔬菜吗？有番茄吗？
Some vegetables?
Nice tomatoes?
把所有的都弄出来，我都要了
Give me everything.
I'll take it all.
蔬菜，水果，洋葱，番茄，洋蓟
Vegetables, fruit,
onions, tomatoes, artichokes
菠萝，意面，米，面粉，鸡蛋，奶酪
pineapples, pasta,
rice, flour, eggs, cheese.
整个店的东西
The whole store.
- 是上帝派你来的吗？
- 当然
- Did God send you?
- He sure did!
别让他们吓到了
Don't let them scare you.
柠檬汁是帮你润喉的
The lemon juice is
for your voice.
好了，爸爸，这是我的考试，不是你的
Okay, Dad.
It's my exam, not yours.
早饭给你能量
Breakfast will give
you energy.
- 别太紧张了
- 我有吗？
- Don't overdo it.
- Am I?
你都快变成直升机了
You're becoming
a helicopter dad.
不对
Wrong.
穿好毛衣，外面冷
Your sweater. It's cold.
我先停车
I'll park first.
这用来做肉汤和备料
This is for broths
and stocks.
- 常，削胡萝卜
- 好的
- Chang, peel carrots.
- Right away.
穆萨，切洋葱
Moussa, chop onions.
提提，清洗蔬菜
Titi, blanch the vegetables.
一个半小时后介绍新菜单！
An hour and a half
to invent a new menu!
一个半小时，这不可能！
An hour and a half.
It's impossible!
但我们得试试，好吗？
But we'll give
it a try, okay?
你好像没能提到阿纳斯塔希拉·弗拉基米尔诺瓦纳
We regret your not mentioning
Anastasila Vladimrovna.
谢谢，但是我觉得
Thank you, but I felt
这和杜斯妥也夫司基这个章节无关
it was irrelevant
in a chapter on Dostoyevsky.
杰拉德，我现在不能说话，什么？
Gerard, I can't talk.
What?
马可这混蛋说他会送蔬菜的！
That bastard Marco said
he'd deliver the vegetables!
我马上来…不好意思
I'm coming...
Excuse me.
对不起，女士，但是…
I'm sorry, madam, but...
对不起让你失望了，我得走了
Sorry to disappoint.
I have to go.
餐厅有麻烦了，你做的很好
Trouble in the restaurant.
That was great work.
我没全看过，但是我很喜欢
I didn't get it all,
but I liked it.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm very proud of you.
对不起但是…
I'm sorry but...
她很棒不是吗？我走了
Isn't she great?
I'm off.
- 爸爸？
- 怎么了？
- Papa?
- What, what?
谢谢
Thanks.
因为早餐？
For breakfast this morning?
早餐很好…晚点见
It was nice... See you later.
我们继续吧，拉加德小姐…
Let's continue,
Miss Lagarde...
不错，亚历山大确实能力非凡
Yeah, Alexandre had
a great reign,
但是他从不做变化
but he hasn't evolved.
他的烹饪都快是史前遗物了
His cuisine is
pre-historical.
我会保持安静的
I'll keep quiet.
我不响影响你们
I don't want
to influence you.
菜单
The menu.
那么？
So?
今天他准备了些什么？
What has he
prepared for us?
- 亚历山大！
- 保罗…你来了
- Alexandre!
- Paul... you came.
我从来没错过你的新菜单
I've never missed any
of your new menus.
你的油漆匠做了这份春季菜单
Your painter did
the Spring menu.
他从哪找到的这些蔬菜？
Where did he find
the vegetables?
街角的杂货店
The corner grocer.
我们死定了
We're dead.
你赶紧叫亚历山大·拉加德过来，这简直不可思议
You must call Alexandre Lagarde.
It's incredible.
我们想向他表示祝贺
We want to
congratulate him.
我们从不知道他有能力
I don't remember him
capable of such subtlety
将现代的东西结合的那么好
allied with
such modernity.
他怎么能够将那么多的情绪融入其中？
How does he put so
much emotion in this?
就像你一个女人子啊拥抱我，把我扔进一个浴盆
It's like a woman hugged me,
threw me in a tub,
用热水帮我擦拭，然后…
sponged me down
with warm water, then...
你们不这样觉得？
Not you?
我对亚历山大很有信心
I expected as much
from Alexandre.
我知道他一直被诽谤
I know that he's
constantly badmouthed
但是对我来说他永远是最棒的
but for me he's always
been the best.
一直都是
Always.
确实
It's true.
亚历山大，我是斯坦尼斯拉斯，给我回电
Alexandre, it's Stanislas.
Call me back.
美食家们想见亚历山大但是我找不到他
The critics want to see
Alexandre but I can't reach him.
我该出去了
I'm going back out.
告诉他们他在忙
Tell them he's
busy working.
这些菜棒极了
These recipes
are magnificent.
开始做乌贼，现在！
Start the calamar, now!
一半传统一半现代
Part traditional,
part molecular!
我服了！
I'm floored!
他怎么做到的？
How did he come
up with it?
我彻底服了！
I'm floored!
他们会为他发明第四个星级的
They'll invent a 4th
star for him!
你在这？
You were here?
- 你也在，马特先生？
- 我可以尝尝吗？
- You too, Mr. Matter?
- Can I taste?
- 爸爸，我不知道你会来
- 你不需要知道
- Dad, I didn't know you came.
- You didn't have to.
都是从杂货店买的？
Everything from
the grocery?
所有我能买到的东西
All I could get
my hands on.
你听到了吗？我想你成功了！
Did you hear?
I think you won!
见到你实在是太高兴了
I am so, so happy
to see you.
来吧，他们在等你，这将是一次巨大的成功
Go on, they're waiting.
It'll be a triumph.
我们之间的关系过去有点紧张
There was some tension
between us recently,
但是过去的都是过去了
but all that's over now.
我想让你继续待在卡古·拉加德
I want you to stay
at Cargo Lagarde.
我坚持
I insist.
我去告诉大家你来了
I'll announce you.
我想时间到了
I think the time has come.
等等…
Hold on...
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
跟我来
Follow me.
女士们先生们，感谢你们喜欢我的春季菜单
Ladies and gentlemen,
you enjoyed my Spring menu.
非常感谢
And I thank you.
但是…
But...
我之前并不在这
I wasn't here earlier.
我在参加我女儿的论文答辩
I watched my daughter
defend her thesis.
她通过了
She passed with honors.
祝贺她
Thanks for her.
欢迎米其林指南的美食家们，低调地来到这里
Hello to the critics from Le Guide,
here incognito.
没有
Not at all.
杰克，过来，过来
Jacky, come here.
Come.
女士们先生们，这为是杰克·波诺
Ladies and gentlemen,
Jacky Bonnot.
他创造了这份春季菜单
He created the Spring menu.
谢谢，主厨
Thanks, chef.
他现在是卡古·拉加德的新主厨了
He is the new chef
at Cargo Lagarde.
是吗，斯坦尼斯拉斯？
Isn't he, Stanislas?
嗯…当然
Umm... yes.
我在寻找一位继任者，然后我找到了他
I was looking for a successor.
And I found him.
所以我在这里告诉大家…
This is why
I'm telling you...
我不再追逐星级了
I'm done chasing stars.
那你准备做什么？
What will you do?
很快你就会知道的
You'll know soon enough.
- 祝贺你
- 谢谢，主厨
- Congratulations.
- Thanks, chef.
祝好运
Good luck.
谢谢大家
Thank you all.
你的有素千层糕简直太棒了
Your mille-feuille was great.
来，把这个给比阿特丽斯
Here, give this to Beatrice.
这次会很顺利的
It'll go over better
this time.
杰克·波诺是我的秘密武器
Jacky Bonnot is
my secret weapon.
先生们
Gentlemen,
我说过我有个惊喜，这就是杰克·波诺！
I said I had a surprise.
It's Jacky Bonnot!
- 过来
- 好的，爸爸
- Come here.
- Yeah, Dad.
我们跳过太多步骤了
We skipped too many steps.
在你掌管集团之前，先去学学怎么鉴别产品的质量
Before you take over the group,
learn to appreciate product quality.
好吧，你是怎么想的？
Fine.
What were you thinking?
我们会有办法的
We'll find something.
- 马特先生？
- 怎么了，朋友？
- Mr. Matter?
- Yes, my friend?
- 我可以那份工作合同吗？
- 现在？
- Can I have a job contract?
- Now?
我需要一份签字的合同，立刻
I need a signed contract,
right away.
- 照他说的做
- 当然，我马上给你签
- Do what he wants!
- Sure. We'll sign you on.
- 立刻
- 再给他签张支票
- Right away.
- Write him a check too.
我会给你张支票
I'll write you a check.
- 好吗？
- 太好了！
- Okay?
- Fine with me!
太棒了，我刚刚做爸爸
Great timing.
I just become a dad.
很好！
Wonderful!
很晚了，我要去纳维尔看我的孩子
I'm late. I have to go to Nevers
to see my baby.
把你的车也给他
Give him your car too.
把你的车给他！
Give him your car!
谢谢
I'd like that.
- 里面有汽油吗？
- 有
- Is there gas?
- Yeah.
高级烹饪将会有大变化
Haute cuisine will
never be the same.
亚历山大·拉加德退出了“星级系统”
Alexandre Lagarde has
given up "the star system".
他的班子现在
His crew now works
为一位年轻的主厨工作，一位新人
for a young chef,
a newcomer.
我们尽量再去找更多的消息
We tried in vain
to find out more.
先生，能给我们介绍一下
Sir, can you tell us
一些关于这位神秘的新主厨吗？
about this mysterious
new chef?
- 嗨，杰克
- 嗨，安东尼
- Hello, Jackie.
- Hello, Antoine.
- 买主厨的工作装？
- 是的！
- Buying your chef's outfit?
- Yes!
这里面随便拿20件给我的属下
And twenty of those
for my crew.
他们会打电话过来的，我想我该先告诉你下
They'll call.
I thought I'd tell you.
终于，安东尼！
So long, Antoine!
…杰克·波诺，年轻的厨艺天才
...Jacky Bonnot,
young culinary genius.
- 你是父亲？
- 是的
- You're the father?
- Yes, I am.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
这都是团队合作，应该归功于我的团队
It's all about teamwork.
I owe it to my crew.
你是说…？不不不，这个是我自己完成的
You meant...?
No, for that I was all alone.
我什么时候能给她做勃艮第炖牛肉
When can I make her
boeuf bourguignon?
两到三年
Two or three years.
- 为什么要这么久？
- 她还是个婴儿
- Why so long?
- She's a baby.
你来很久了？
Have you been
here long?
她真漂亮
She's so beautiful.
一切顺利吗？
Did it all go well?
一份工作合同
A job contract.
太棒了
Excellent.
- 我必须得告诉你…
- 我也得告诉你
- I have to tell you...
- I have to tell you too.
那你愿意嫁给我了？
So you'll be my wife?
真正的求次婚啊，这太无聊了
Propose for real.
This is all so lame.
真正的求婚？
Propose for real?
就像…
Like...
比阿特丽斯
Beatrice,
我的挚爱
my love,
你愿意嫁给我吗？
will you be my wife?
我愿意！
I do!
等等
Hold on.
告诉我，你第一次撒谎是什么时候？
Just tell me.
When was the first lie?
为什么我们还没技术上在一起？
Why weren't we
technically together?
技术上来说我记不清了
Technically I can't
remember too well.
大家好
Hello, everyone.
欢迎观看我们的新节目
Welcome to our
new show,
现在是每周一期
which is now weekly
- 亚历山大的烹饪指南
- 以及杰克的
- Alexandre's Cuisine...
- And Jacky's.
杰克，我们要吃的！我们要吃的！我们要吃的…
Jacky, give us food!
我们的第一期节目，将会介绍一道经典菜肴
For our first show,
we're starting off with a classic.
烤排骨
Grilled côte de boeuf.
- 今天是个大日子
- 当然！
- Today is a big day.
- Sure is!
今天，米其林指南更新了
Today, Le Guide came out
感谢杰克，卡古·拉加德保住了三星级
and thanks to Jacky,
Cargo Lagarde kept its 3 stars.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
你保持了15年的三星级
You kept your 3 stars
for fifteen years
感谢你非凡的技巧
thanks to your
extraordinary skills.
你不待在卡古·拉加德了
You're no longer
at Cargo Lagarde.
为什么跑去纳维尔当厨师？
Why did you go and become
a cook in Nevers?
纳维尔是个优雅的地方！
Neat place, Nevers!
这里我们有一些录像
Here we have
some neat images
关于你在新餐厅的工作
of you cooking
in your new restaurant.
请享用
For you.
请慢用您的午餐
Enjoy your lunch.
我在这…和卡罗尔一起
And here I am... with Carole.
她是这的老板
She runs the place.
我们决定在客人中间工作
We decided to work
amid everyone.
我感觉…好像又变年轻了
And I'm starting...
to feel young again.
看看东西做的如何了
Look how nice this is.
这肉快好了
I think this meat
is almost ready.
- 看我带了什么
- 迷迭香？
- And look what I brought.
- Rosemary?
- 美味
- 这是干嘛的？
- Delicious.
- What is it for?
- 放排骨里
- 没门
- The côte de boeuf.
- No way.
- 为什么不？
- 牛脊肉里不能加迷迭香！
- Why not?
- No rosemary on rib roast!
你在开玩笑吗？
You kidding?
我不会让你毁掉这道烤肉的！
I will not let you
ruin this roast!
这有果汁和黄油，这些才是应该加的
There's juice and butter.
That's what counts.
- 记住我们还在直播
- 直播我也得说
- Remember we're live.
- I'll say it live.
- 把肉给我
- 绝不！
- Give me the meat.
- No!
迷迭香会掩盖掉味道的
It'll mask the flavor.
过来
Come here.
烤排骨里面不能加迷迭香
No rosemary on
côte de boeuf.
回来！你要去哪？
Come back!
Where are you going?
我宁愿倒掉它也不放迷迭香
I'd rather drown it
than use rosemary.
只不过一点迷迭香！
Just a little rosemary!
那怎么不再加点百里香？还有香葱！
Why not some thyme too?
And chives!
切掉
Cut.
呱，呱…
Quack, quack...
切，结束
Cut. End-slate.
=-全片完，谢谢观赏-=
更多精彩影视，尽在HDCHINA.ORG